## Nicholas J. Bass

(562) 743-5434 nickbass12@gmail.com LinkedIn: /nickbass128161

Aerospace Corporation 2310 E. El Segundo Blvd, El Segundo, CA 90245

2 May 2016

Hello Aerospace Business Intelligence Team,

I want to express my interest in your Business Intelligence Internship. I believe my background in clerical work and customer service will benefit your team and its work.

My responsibilities as a student clerical assistant include supporting daily operations of the University textbook office in preparation and maintenance of course materials, as well as creating, processing, and stocking purchase orders for product shipment. On a daily basis I am responsible for placing orders with wholesalers and publishers, researching and tracking open invoices, and updating course information.

As a technician's assistant for King Bee Mechanical I practice problem solving and attention to detail in the large and small scale of operations as well as being responsible for office organization, logging job information, and financial management.

Throughout my courses in Information Systems I have learned to gather data, analyze trends, and communicate results. During the end of term buyback last December, one of our busiest times, I was in charge of using logistics to optimize station coverage. I gathered raw transaction information and generated a report to determine which times throughout the day require more or less coverage.

My experience has taught me how to communicate and work well with a team to complete personal tasks as well as team tasks. Through my time in scouting I learn how and when to lead a team and work within groups to achieve goals to better the whole organization.

My resume provides additional information on my background and qualifications. I look forward to meet with you soon to discuss my future with The Aerospace Corporation.

Thank you for your consideration,

Nicholas Bass

Nick Bass

# Nicholas J. Bass

(562) 743-5434

nickbass12@gmail.com LinkedIn: /nickbass128161

#### **Education**

California State University Long Beach

Major: Business Administration - Management Information Systems Fall 2012 - Present Minor: Web Technologies & Applications Fall 2014 - Present

Current Cumulative GPA: 3.207

**Expected Graduation** May 2017

#### **Work Experience**

Forty-Niner Shops Inc.

 Student Clerical Assistant Nov 2014 - Present

Create, process, and receive purchase orders

Assist in determining appropriate order amounts based on sales trends

Analyze customer trends to maintain proper station coverage

Generate reports to improve Buyback efficiency

Organized a Digital Textbook marketing campaign

Fall 2013 - Nov 2014 **Book Information** 

Provided exceptional customer service to students and staff alike

Created a welcoming environment for customers

Supported Frontline cashiers and cross trained employees

Long Beach Area Council – Boy Scouts of America

Sea Base Aquatics Summer Day Camp - Office Manager Jun 2014 - Aug 2014

Managed office and office obligations

Provided customer service and support to campers and parents

. Registered campers

Sea Base Aquatics Summer Day Camp - Office Manager Jun 2013 - Aug 2013

Managed office and office obligations

Simplified and consolidated camp processing system

Generated seasonal financial reports

King Bee Mechanical

Office Assistant Aug 2013 - Present

Catalogue Delivery Tickets, Invoices, and Statements

Record job information

Document & Deposit Checks

Technician's Assistant Aug 2012 - Present

Installed industrial and residential HVAC systems

Solving problems unique to each job site

### **Volunteer Experience**

ΠΚΦ Push America/The Ability Experience Jan 2013 - May 2015 **Eagle Scout Projects** July 2006 – Mar 2012

### **Extracurricular Activities**

Sept 2000 – May 2012 Boy Scouts of America Eagle Scout March 28, 2012

 Lead scouts in building, installing, & refurbishing kindergarten play area

Communicated between Troop, School, & Long Beach Unified School District

Organized & fundraised an \$1,100 Project

2000 - 2009 Tae Kwon Do

Nov 2006 Second Degree Black Belt First Degree Black Belt Dec 2003

ПКФ Pi Kappa Phi Fraternity Jan 2013 - May 2015

Class Secretary

AMA American Marketing Association

Sept 2014 – May 2015

ISSA Information Systems Student Association

Sept 2015 – Present

Leadership Training by Edward Professional Advisors Oct 2015 - Dec 2015

Canoeing

Skills

Microsoft Office

- Word, PowerPoint, Excel, Access, Project, Visio

**Event Planning** 

- Eagle Project 2012

Excel Business Modelina

**Customer Service** 

Application Programming Python

Web coding

- WordPress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, PHP

**Interests** 

Camping

Hiking & Backpacking

Fishing

Skiina

Surfing